▍2026 国家银行公开赛（多伦多）半决赛
莱巴金娜 5-7 6-2 6-2 高芙 · 赛后场上采访
A superb win.
一场精彩的胜利
And when she's in that form,
她进入这种状态的时候
she's unstoppable.
没人能挡得住
Elena, I said it last night,
埃琳娜 我昨晚说过
I'm saying it again tonight.
今晚我还要再说一遍
You have ice in your veins.
你的血管里全是冰
What a performance yet again.
又是一次了不起的表现
Congratulations.
恭喜你
The crowd still here
看台上还坐满了人
to make sure they can cheer you on.
就是为了给你加油
You spent 11 and a half hours on the court
这一届赛事里 你已经
at this tournament.
在场上站了11个半小时
It's 1:00 a.m.
现在是凌晨一点
Eastern.
美东时间
How did you maintain
你是怎么保持住
your focus despite what I'd imagine
专注力的 我猜
is some fatigue?
你肯定很累了
Well, I don't know. I feel like uh
我也不知道 我感觉
as you said I stayed so many hours
就像你说的 呆了这么久
on the court that maybe some shots
在场上 可能有些球
are just coming out from my racket
就这样自己从球拍里飞出去了
and uh also at important moment I got
而且关键时刻
a bit lucky with the line on the return
接发球判线上也沾了点运气
and uh again was just trying to fight
我就是一直在拼
and uh guys thank you so much for staying
谢谢大家留到这么晚
so late it's been a long day.
今天真是漫长的一天
The last time you played Coco
你上一次和高芙交手
was in Toronto.
也是在多伦多
It also went three sets.
那场也打了三盘
How do you operate knowing the margin
你知道对她
for error is so small against her?
容错空间很小 是怎么应对的
Yeah, it's true.
是啊 确实是这样
Last time we played,
我们上次交手
it was also such a battle
也是一场恶战
and even in the on the practices,
就连平时一起训练
it's always kind of close uh close matches.
打起来也总是很胶着
So, uh yeah, I was just trying to focus
所以我就尽量专注
my serve helped me especially in the end.
发球在最后帮了我很大的忙
And I feel like
我感觉
in the first set we were uh playing both well,
首盘我们俩都打得不错
but then I rushed a little bit and uh uh yeah,
后来我有点着急
I'm just glad that I managed to win again
我很高兴自己还是赢了下来
in three sets.
打满三盘的这场
You were so close to being a finalist
你去年夏天在蒙特利尔
in Montreal last summer.
差一点就打进决赛
You were a finalist here in Toronto.
这次在多伦多 你真的打进了
How proud are you
这一周你拼出来的这一切
of the fight you've shown this week?
你有多骄傲
Very proud.
非常骄傲
Very proud. Also also with team I think we
非常骄傲 而且和团队一起
did a great uh preparation.
我们准备得也很充分
So now the most important just to keep
现在最重要的就是
on going no matter of the result tomorrow.
不管明天结果如何都要往前走
Just try to to enjoy
就是尽量去享受
and uh yeah keep keep on playing,
一直打下去
keep on trying and hopefully go deep
一直去拼 希望在每一站
on all the tournaments.
都能走得更远一些
Well, Elena, go rest up.
好了 埃琳娜 去好好休息吧
You've earned it and you'll fight
这是你应得的 明天
for the title tomorrow.
你还要为冠军再拼一场
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Thank you. Thank you very much.
谢谢 非常感谢你们